<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<reviews itemIdentifier="gilda-1946-colorized">
  <review>
    <reviewtitle>12 30 23 Dear Mr. Colorizer........</reviewtitle>
    <reviewbody>TO BOTH GEORGE FERGUS AND JTDIVER

Re Colorization: May I share this with you?  Some time back - @ a year or so ago, I found IA had a colorized version of Gilda [my 2nd most valued film.]  I researched it but was totally underwhelmed – there was nothing good about what was done to this brilliant film on IA.  The perpetrators actually stamped THEIR LOGOS and  insignias, which appear on each frame; further, they contrived it such that a viewer is unable to remove their advertising directly opposite to the actual film, despite all attempts to enlarge the film to NOT be distracted by each frame's advertising of the “colorizers.”  I totally chided them that long ago, bringing up their faults in the desecration of this totally-brilliant-in-every-way-film.   Their response was that it was required of them to do these things.  A year+ went by and I was still distressed about Gilda's ill treatment, then discovered a GREAT IA COLORIZER [George Fergus or a pseudonym.]  I totally fell in love watching brilliantly-colorized films I watched as a little kid.  Then I watched films of people I have NEVER watched before – for lack of colorization and my lack of knowing anything about these actors.  I have converted myself since.  I LOVE THESE COLORIZATIONS.  They show no evidence of have prior, colorless existences – therefore to me, they are NEW FILMS.   That being said I implored the 'Great Colorizer' to colorize Gilda.  Meanwhile unbeknownst to me I was actually hungering for and sorry for the beauty that good colorization would give to Gilda.  So I went online to try to teach myself how to colorize one film myself – Gilda.  All to no avail.  I am totally unfit for the project.  Meanwhile I researched the badly colorized version on IA and discovered that it had been remastered by UCLA but not colorized.  It occurred to me to contact them for a good new colorization.  But with one thing and another I got busy and  never contacted them.  Then just yesterday while looking for some colorized  film to watch my eye was caught.  There, among all the others was Gilda in brilliant  –  almost translucent color.  SHE HAD BEEN COLORIZED by none other than George Fergus! ! ! ! ! Holy Moly Batman!  I was totally overwhelmed and before the possibility of a mistake occurring I downloaded her.  OMG I watched it over and over again until I fell asleep and woke late this morning.
					    - - - -

Hello, pen pal, magic genie, archiver, JTDIVER.  As I've  mentioned before my system [loving and using VLC for a thousand years CANNOT bring up really big films so I had to install Potplayer – they are marvelous and so extensively capable with all things movies that there seems nothing they cannot do.]  The only fault I find with them is ME – I am woefully lacking both verbally and  intellectually to do much with their FREE and brilliant software.  All that is to say that when I scan your films to see which I can download I look to size, first – therefore if correct, I guess I missed your previous listing of the Long Kiss Goodnight and so felt you would get a kick out of seeing it.  Sorry for confusing you and I hope that clears up the misunderstanding of ME offering to send YOU the film.  How funny that now seems to me – that I would have access to a film you DID NOT HAVE ACCESS TO – poor me.  Hope this clears up part 1 of my confusing you.

As for The Women – I LOVE IT – and watch it once or twice a year – it never gets old to me.  Over the years I've had to slow the dialogue down somewhat inasmuch as one can miss so much of the brilliance of the words themselves.  I could be wrong but think it was written by Clair Booth Luce and/or 1 or 2 others of her peers.  Too, I LOVE sharp-tongued women and the brilliance they throw around like bread crumbs to hungry fish.  I've tried watching other representations of this film – and found them wholly lacking – tho' the actors were good, the sharpness was missing.  This is why no-one has made another one – The Women is literally [in any universe yet-to-be-found, including ours] simply, THE BEST.  I hope this clears up part 2 of my confusing you.  Writing this brings tears to my eyes – I cannot believe that you are colorizing my favorite film.  I am totally overwhelmed and tears are falling.  However and whatever the outcome – is of less import than the kindnesses you have bestowed upon me.  Words are insufficient to express my heart's feelings right now.

Thank you so much for all you do [I'm sure you hear that a lot.]  I SO APPRECIATE YOU BOTH SOOOO MUCH! ! ! ! ! ! !  Everyday I watch one of your movies I live yet another day.  You will never know how much all of your efforts mean to me.  Please never diminish  the quality of what you do – somewhere and everywhere on IA people really do appreciate you both whether they write to you or not.  I am one little cog here among perhaps millions of appreciative albeit silent followers.

  

</reviewbody>
    <stars>5</stars>
    <reviewer>needinreadin</reviewer>
    <reviewdate>2023-12-30 21:23:16</reviewdate>
    <createdate>2023-12-30 06:29:38</createdate>
    <reviewer_itemname>@needinreadin</reviewer_itemname>
  </review>
  <review>
    <reviewtitle>bleeding colorized</reviewtitle>
    <reviewbody>Only film that was colorized properly was Tyrone Power's The Mark Of Zorro 1940 which I have.That said Gilda colorized is a disappoint, I stick with my 1080p b/w Gilda. </reviewbody>
    <stars>0</stars>
    <reviewer>Odin55</reviewer>
    <reviewdate>2024-02-04 05:59:12</reviewdate>
    <createdate>2024-02-04 05:59:12</createdate>
    <reviewer_itemname>@odin55</reviewer_itemname>
  </review>
  <info>
    <num_reviews>2</num_reviews>
    <avg_rating>5.00</avg_rating>
  </info>
</reviews>
